让我们总结一下本讲座的一些要点。
Let's summarise some of the main points from this lecture.
我们讨论了机器人如何知道物体在其环境中的位置。机器人实际上并不是
We talked about how a robot knows where objects are in its environment. A robot doesn't actually
测量其工具尖端的位置，从关节角度测量和推断
measure the position of its tool tip, it is inferred from joint angle measurements and
来自运动模型。它知道刀尖需要的笛卡尔坐标
from a kinematic model. It knows the Cartesian coordinate of where the tool tip needs to
走向世界，运动控制器的工作就是把工具提到那里。
go in the world, and it’s the job of the motion controller to take the tool tip there.
这个过程可能会出现许多问题;传感器可能存在错误，
A number of things can go wrong with this process; there could be errors in the sensors,
运动模型可能存在误差，我们可能不知道机器人的基准位置
there could be errors in the kinematic model, we may not know the base position of the robot
准确地说，我们可能不太准确地知道电路板的位置。所有的
accurately, we may not know the location of the circuit board very accurately. All of
这些问题对我们构建现代工业机器人的方式产生了影响
these issues have consequences on the way we construct a modern industrial robot and
它们通常会导致成本增加。
they generally tend to lead to increased cost.
我们可以将其与人类解决问题的方式进行对比;例如穿针。
We can contrast that with the way human beings solve problems; for instance threading a needle.
我用眼睛引导或引导线的末端穿过针孔。
I use my eyes to guide or to steer the end of the thread through the hole in the needle.
如果我们将这个问题更加示意地考虑在哪里，我们试图对齐两端的结尾
If we consider this problem a bit more schematically where we're trying to align the end of two
对象，我们可以考虑三维笛卡尔空间中的任务，我们也可以看一下
objects, we can consider the task in the three-dimensional Cartesian space and we can also look at that
任务用相机。我们可以看一下正在实现的任务的二维表示。
task with a camera. We can look at a two-dimensional representation of that task being achieved.
我们谈到了如何仅使用单个图像中的信息实际上提供的信息不足
We talked about how using information from just a single image actually provides insufficient
在三维空间中可靠地执行此任务的信息。但实际上我们可以
information to reliably perform this task in three-dimensional space. But we can actually
在两个摄像机视图中同时执行任务，对齐红色和蓝色对象，
perform the task simultaneously in two camera views, aligning the red and blue objects,
如果发生这种情况，那么在真实的三维世界中，红色和蓝色物体也会对齐。
and if that happens, then in the real three-dimensional world the red and blue objects will also become aligned.
我们谈到了移动相机时会发生什么。相机有六度
We talked about what happens when we move a camera. The camera's got six degrees of
自由;其速度可以用三个平移速度分量来描述
freedom; its velocity can be described in terms of three translational velocity components
和三个旋转速度分量。如果我们想象相机正在看
and three rotational velocity components. If we imagine that the camera is looking at
一个恒定距离的常规点阵列，然后是每个相机速度分量
a regular array of points a constant distance away, then each of the camera velocity components
导致图像平面上这些点的相当独特的运动模式。和这里
results in a fairly unique pattern of motion of those points on the image plane. And here
我们可以看到由于速度而被称为光流的运动模式
we can see the patterns of motion, which are referred to as optical flow, due to velocity
在X方向上，Z方向上的速度或绕Z轴的旋转速度。
in the X direction, velocity in the Z direction or rotational velocity around the Z axis.
模式是相当明显的，但其中一些有点相似，特别是
The patterns are fairly distinct but some of them are a little bit similar, and in particular
X方向的速度与旋转引起的运动模式非常相似
velocity in the X direction is quite similar to the pattern of motion induced by rotation
围绕Y轴;它们看起来非常相似，但相似之处实际上取决于它们
around the Y axis; they look quite similar, but the amount of similarity actually depends
关于镜头的焦距。对于大焦距，模糊性非常明显。
on the focal length of the lens. For a large focal length, the ambiguity is quite pronounced.
随着焦距变小，模糊性不那么明显。这种模糊之间
As the focal length gets smaller, the ambiguity is much less evident. This ambiguity between
vX和omega-Y，我们也在vY和omega-X之间看到，那里有一个对称性。
vX and omega-Y, we also see between vY and omega-X, there's a symmetry there.
由六个向量描述的相机速度与之间的关系
The relationship between the camera velocity which is described by a six vector and the
图像平面上的点的速度由图像雅可比矩阵描述。
velocity of the point on the image plane, is described by the image Jacobian matrix.
图像雅可比矩阵告诉我们，对于特定的相机运动，点将如何
The image Jacobian matrix tells us, for a particular camera motion, how points will
在图像平面上移动。我们可以转过来说我们想要的
move on the image plane. We can turn this around and saying instead we want to have
图像平面上的特定速度，以便从初始移动形状
a particular velocity on the image plane in order to move a shape from perhaps an initial
查看所需的视图。所以现在我们有了图像平面速度，我们可以反转这种关系
view to a desired view. So now we have the image plane velocity, we can invert the relationship
并确定我们需要的相机速度，以实现我们所需的对象视图。
and determine the camera velocity that we need in order to achieve our desired view of the object.
雅可比图像将像素速度与相机速度和图像雅可比相关联
The image Jacobian relates pixel velocity to camera velocity, and the image Jacobian
本身是许多参数的函数。它取决于点的坐标
itself is a function of many parameters. It depends on the coordinate of the point on
在图像平面上，它取决于点在三维空间中远离相机的距离
the image plane, it depends on how far the point is away from the camera in three-dimensional
空间，这取决于焦距。我们可以在许多不同的方面重新安排这个等式
space and it depends on the focal length. We can re-arrange this equation in many different
方法;也许我们知道像素速度和Z，以及u和v，然后我们可以确定什么
ways; perhaps we know pixel velocity and Z, and u and v, and then we can determine what
相机速度是。我们可以用这个图像雅可比矩阵玩很多技巧。
the camera velocity is. There are many tricks that we can play with this image Jacobian matrix.